One commonly overlooked cause of acne on
TRT is an immune system reaction to the
carrier oil. Can you take Accutane well
on TRT? And if so, is there anything to
be careful about? Yeah, I'll answer that
one. Of course, you can take Accutane.
The that's the brand name. Eotinoin is
the molecule name, the generic name. Uh
so it's used for acne and sibic skin. If
you take Accutin, your skin will dry
out. So being on TRT will stimulate the
seabone production. So it will even be
better and lessen the side effects of
drying out. So I can't see why you
shouldn't um take them together if you
both need them. Of course I have a lot
of teenagers on um Accutane isotriinoine
and of course they also have high levels
of testosterone. So I don't see any
problem. Um the things that you should
be careful about are the things uh
drying out your skin ex especially your
lips. Um exposure to the sun your be
most more sensitive to burning if you
are have a fair skin type and uh not
becoming pregnant for the women or trans
men. Now um those those are the most
important things.
Yeah it's very important men don't
become pregnant. Um yeah and just to
just to kind of touch on the the topic
obviously the reason why people are
looking to take Accutane is because of
acne. One thing that we find uh in
Australia one thing that we're blessed
with in Australia is we have access to
cipionate ananthate sustenon every
different carrier oil. Um, and one thing
that I know Jordan Grant uh has recently
started speaking about as well because
um when people become aware of this then
it becomes quite obvious is that one of
the causes of acne. We know that TRT in
some circumstances will make acne worse.
If the dose is too high, if the
injection frequency is too low, these
things will either cause acne or they'll
make acne worse because the levels are
too high. there's too much sebum
production. Um, there's a lot of reasons
that everyone kind of knows about for
that, but one commonly overlooked cause
of acne on TRT is an immune system
reaction to the carrier oil. So, what I
found is about somewhere between 1 in 10
and 1 in 20 guys will react to cotton
seed oil, sesame oil, or grape seed oil.
So, and I I was doing a case study the
other day that I was putting together
for my friends over at Victory. You
know, we had a guy come in who had, you
know, free testosterone level in like
the top quartile of the reference range.
So, still within range. Uh he'd been on
treatment for six months doing three
injections a week, you know, perfect
diet, no alcohol, no other inflammatory
markers. And he was saying, you know, I
want to put my dose up because I don't
have symptom resolution, but my acne is
just horrific. and same and you know in
Australia the quite common testosterone
preparation is primmaestin which is a
pre-loaded syringe from Baya which comes
in castor oil and we've seen this a
bunch of times where if we transfer
these guys over to an MCTbased solution
which I think is the best because it
draws and injects really quickly it's a
much thinner oil so you can have a much
quicker injection process you can use a
smaller needle it will flow really well
through a 29 gauge um so not only is it
a nicer oil for everyone to use, but
it's very very unlikely to have an
immune reaction to MCT and acne
completely resolved. So, if someone's in
a situation being like TRT is giving me
acne and you know, I've dialed in all
other aspects of what should be causing
acne problems and I've I've done
everything else, see if your provider
can swap the carrier oil ideally to MCT,
otherwise to grape seed oil if that's
not the one you're currently using. And
that can be really helpful for a lot of
guys with these stubborn issues.